Guide to the Yehuda Amichai Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Yehuda Amichai, 1952-1999; Series II; 8.97; (22 boxes)
  - POETRY
    - Individual poems
      - "Dayagim Marokaim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 915)
        Includes "Tehilim"
      - "Dedi yeled ben 11 1/2," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 916)
      - "Degalim ahar ha-hag..." draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 917)
      - "Derekh kol ha'arets," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 918)
      - "ha-Dirah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 919)
      - "Don John" draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 920)
      - "El (yadid) she-hu kohen," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 921)
      - "Eli avivo," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 922)
      - "Elohai, ha-neshamah," draft, holograph, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 923)
      - "Elohim merahem al yalde ha-gan," draft, holograph, and printed version (Box 28, Folder 924)
      - "En Gedi," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 925)
      - [Empty folder] (Box 28, Folder 926)
      - "Etsel omanuto shel ilem," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 927)
      - "For Stanley and Jane Moss," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1990-96, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 928)
      - "Gan," draft, holograph (Box 28, Folder 929)
      - "Ganim be-Yisrael," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 930)
      - "Geshem," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 931)
      - "Geshem bi-Yerushalayim," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 932)
      - "Gomet," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 933)
      - "H.P.I." draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 934)
      - "Hadvah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 935)
      - "Hag Atsmaut," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 936)
      - "Hag ha-zikaron," draft, holograph (Box 28, Folder 937)
      - "Hagigat kayits," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 938)
      - "Hagim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 939)
      - "Halikhah be-sheleg..." draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 940)
      - "Halom," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 941)
      - "Har Meron," draft, holograph (Box 28, Folder 942)
      - "Har Tsyion erev tsiyon," drafts, holograph (Box 28, Folder 943)
      - "Hashkahah kadima ha-zikaron," draft, holograph (Box 28, Folder 944)
      - "Havai Kopernikus," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 945)
      - "Hegyah ha-zeman le-halek," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 946)
      - "ha-Hidhude beniyah shibuts," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 947)
      - "Historya," draft, holograph, corrected, 1982 Jun (Box 28, Folder 948)
      - "ha-Hozer," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 949)
      - "Hupat..." draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 950)
      - "Hymn to a Marriage," holograph, corrected, [1989?] (Box 28, Folder 951)
      - "I am Sitting Here Now," printed publicity, 1995 Jan (Box 28, Folder 952)
      - "Im eshkahekh, Yerushalayim," printed version, A Service for Israeli Independence Day, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 953)
      - "Imiy aftah li et kol ha-olam," printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 954)
      - "Iri," printed version (2 copies), 1989 (Box 28, Folder 955)
      - "Ish u-mekomo," printed version, Yediot Ahronot, photocopy, 1985 Mar 25 (Box 28, Folder 956)
      - "Kalevet," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 957)
      - "ha-Karbon ha-amiti," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 958)
      - "Karov be-rahok," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 959)
      - "Ke-hovot Nyu York," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 960)
      - "Ke-mishmar ha-emek," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 961)
      - "ha-Kenot horef," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 962)
      - "Ke-patyo," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 963)
      - "ha-Kibutsim shel ha-talmudim," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 964)
      - "Kinah," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 965)
      - "Kineret," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 966)
        Includes "ha-Yeled eneni"
      - "Kiriah be-eyn kerem," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 967)
      - "ha-Kiti le-naarti," printed version, broadside, [1992?]
      - "Kivun mezamen," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 968)
      - "Kelalit," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 969)
      - "Kohav ha-Yarden," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 970)
      - "Le-Aryeh Gilat," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1996 (Box 28, Folder 971)
      - "Leat ve-leolam," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 972)
      - "Le-haserim," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 973)
      - "Le-hatunah shel Yifat u-Tsevi," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 974)
      - "Le-liliyon..." draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 975)
      - "Le-regel ha-regel haholah sheli," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 976)
      - "Le-shir," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 977)
      - "Le-shir ha-aron," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 28, Folder 978)
      - "Le-yad ha-kevish," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 979)
      - "Le-yad ramzor," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 980)
      - "Le-yad Sarah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 981)
      - "Li-metso," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 982)
      - ["Lito-fav"?], draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 983)
      - "Li-zekor Professor Fegenboim," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 984)
      - "Lo Muhanim," printed version, corrected, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 985)
      - "Maayan aharit ha-Yamim," printed version, 1991 Mar 22 (Box 28, Folder 986)
      - "Made in Holland," manuscript in unidentified hand, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 987)
      - "ha-Makom she-bo anu tsodekim," Supreme Court documents, photocopies, 1977, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 988)
      - "Makot mitsrayim meshel ve-ahavah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 989)
      - "Masaot Binyamin ha-Aharon mi-Tudelah," drafts, holograph, corrected, and printed versions, Webster Review, [1971?], 1977 (Box 28, Folder 990)
      - "Me-atit," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 991)
      - "Me-az," printed version, Martyrology, [1997-1998] (Box 28, Folder 992)
      - "Me-en ahavah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 993)
      - "Me-en mitsvah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 994)
        Includes "Mis hak historyah"
      - "Mekarim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 995)
      - "Merutseh," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 996)
      - "Metsits," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 997)
      - "Min ha-nesiah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 998)
      - "Min neroto," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 999)
      - "Min pirtsah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1000)
      - "Mis hak historyah," draft, holograph
        See: "Me-en mitsvah," Box 28, folder 994
      - "Mis hak [tefem?]," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1001)
      - "Mi-tokh mahberet Nyu York," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1002)
      - "Mitsri be-Tel Aviv," draft, typescript, 1978 Feb 25 (Box 29, Folder 1003)
      - "Mi-zeman le-zeman," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1004)
      - "Mi-zeman lo shamati me-even," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 29, Folder 1005)
      - "Motetin," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 29, Folder 1006)
      - "Muzeon Yisra'el," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1007)
      - "Nahar," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1008)
      - "Nasot," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1009)
      - "Nedidot ve-kayits," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1010)
      - "Nedunyah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1011)
      - "Nerot shabat," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1012)
      - "Nesiah le-sedeh," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1013)
      - "Nesiah le-Yeru," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1014)
      - "Olai nitsraf she-shaot ha-am..." draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1015)
      - "Onot," printed version, 1956 Sep 26 (Box 29, Folder 1016)
      - "Osefe Mendalshtam," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1017)
      - "Osher," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1018)
      - "Pegishah im atsmi," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1019)
      - ["Penda"?], draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1020)
      - "Pene ami," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1021)
      - "Pitriyot," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1022)
      - "Purim ve-Hanukah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1023)
      - "Raah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1024)
      - "Rabanim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1025)
      - "Ragli rak kele tahburah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1026)
      - "Rega zeh," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1027)
      - "Rikudim ba-bayit ha-shakhen, draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1028)
      - "Rosh ir," extended version, drafts, holograph, corrected, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 1029)
        Includes letter from Shulamit Eisner
      - "Ruah O'mayim," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1030)
      - "Sehiyah bi-verekhah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1031)
      - "Shalom bi-Yerushalayim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1032)
      - "Sharsheret...," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1033)
      - "Shavua le-ven pesah," draft, holograph, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 1034)
      - ["Shayna"?], draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1035)
      - "Sheka," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1036)
      - "Sheli havanah shel ahavah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1037)
      - "Shene shire ha-tsav," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1038)
      - "Shir ahavah le-Hanah," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1039)
      - "Shir ahavah shel hayal zaken," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1040)
      - "Shir be-viyushah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1041)
      - "Shir erets tsiyon," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1042)
      - "Shir hadash," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1043)
      - "Shir haganah," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1044)
      - "Shir hozer le-shimush atsmi," draft holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1045)
      - "Shir kinkoti," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1046)
      - "Shir li-fetihah," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1047)
      - "Shir moledet," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1048)
      - "Shir Negev," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1049)
      - "Shir [sheynah?]," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1050)
      - "Shir setav," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1051)
      - "Shirah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1052)
      - "Shirat Neged..." draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1053)
      - "Shirey ha-arets," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1054)
      - "Shirey Mezuzah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1055)
      - "Shirey shaker ve-yofi," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1056)
      - "Shirey shirim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1057)
      - "Shirey Yerushalayim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1058)
      - "Shirim kemo mikhyah kaful," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1059)
      - "Shitah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1060)
      - "Shitah Tibet yashan," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1061)
      - "Shiva," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1062)
      - "Shivah batay: shir le-Nahalat Shivah," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1063)
      - "Sihah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1064)
      - "Sihah al zaken," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1065)
      - "Simhah sheketah be-ihur," English translation, printed version, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1066)
      - "Siyum shel shir," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1067)
        Includes "ha-Zihronot"
      - "Tafrit: zerihat hamah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1068)
      - "Tahalikh tsiyoni..." draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1069)
      - "ha-Tahanah," broadsides, 1979
      - "Tahanah Sarah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1070)
      - "Tahat [be-shaal?] dayarin," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1071)
      - "Tanakh," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1072)
      - "Teh ve-lashon ahavah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1073)
      - "Tehilim," draft, holograph
        See: "Dayagim Marokaim," Box 28, folder 915
      - "Tel Aviv," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1074)
      - "Temunah ishah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1075)
      - "Temunat Lailah," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1076)
      - "Teva," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1077)
      - "Tiyul..." draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1078)
      - "Tiyul el Har Tsiyon," draft, holograph (Box 29, Folder 1079)
      - "Tiyul min Givat..." draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1080)
      - "Tiyul moadon sport," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1978, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1081)
      - "Tiyul ve-atsikot," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1082)
      - "Tiyul Yehudah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1083)
      - "Tiyulim im ima," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1084)
      - "Tohnit ir," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1085)
      - "Tosefet la-hazon ha-shalom," printed version, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1086)
      - "Tsalam hovev," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1087)
      - "Tunikah shel ahavah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1088)
      - "U-mi yizkor et ha-zokhrim," printed versions, photocopy, 1998, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1089)
      - "Universitah," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1090)
      - "Valdi," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1091)
      - "Ve-ahar kakh," printed version, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1092)
      - "Ve-tsirat adam," draft, holograph, 1988 May (Box 30, Folder 1093)
      - "We Do Not Have Unknown Soldiers," draft, typescript, 1967 Jun (Box 30, Folder 1094)
      - "Who Are You, Ivan Schwebel," offprint, Ariel (2 copies), 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1095)
      - "Yaldah mefonot ba-otobus," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1096)
      - "Yeladim," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1097)
      - "ha-Yeled eneni," draft, holograph, corrected
        See: "Kineret," Box 28, folder 966
      - "Yerushalayim be-geshem," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1098)
      - "Yerushalayim ve-Yeriho," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1099)
      - "Yeshivah im Yoni be-gan [tsavta?]," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1100)
      - "Yeshu Shoneh," draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1101)
      - "Yom Kipur" drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1102)
      - "Yom Shabat boker," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1103)
      - "Yom, shanah, la-mut oti," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1104)
      - "Yomayim li-fene hanituah," drafts, holograph, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1105)
      - "ha-Zihronot," draft, holograph
        See: "Siyum shel shir," Box 29, folder 1067
      - "Zihronot (ha-tekhelet nikur)," drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1106)
      - "Zikim," draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1107)
      - Unidentified draft fragments, 1966-1967, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1108-1115)
      - Unidentified draft fragments, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1116-1117)
    - Translations
      - Arabic, 1990-1994, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1118)
      - Bengali, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 1119)
      - Chinese, 1990-1993, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1120)
      - Dutch, 1971-1994 (Box 31, Folder 1121)
      - English (A-S), 1973-1995, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1122-1125)
      - English (T-Z), 1973-1990, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1126-1129)
      - French, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1130)
      - German, 1981-1990, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1131-1135)
        Includes drafts in hand of Yehuda Amichai
      - Greek, 1973, 1980 (Box 32, Folder 1136)
      - Gujurati, 1979 Jan (Box 32, Folder 1137)
      - Hungarian, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 1138)
      - Italian, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1139)
      - Polish, 1991, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1140)
      - Romanian, 1978, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1141)
      - Russian, 1990-1997, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1142-1144)
      - Spanish, 1964-1996, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1145-1147)
      - Swedish, 1983-1998, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1148)
      - Polyglot, 1994, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1149)
    - Adaptations
      - "Aval mah asita lemaan nafshekha?" musical setting, manuscript, 1984
      - "Be-tokh zeman gadol," program, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1150)
      - "Contemporary Sounds," printed program, 1987 May 23
      - "Dramatis Personae," program, dance concert, computer printout, 1996 (Box 33, Folder 1151)
      - Eshkolot, printed version, 1990 (Box 33, Folder 1152)
        Includes musical settings of "El male rahamim"
      - "Geshem ba-sadeh kerav," musical setting, 1983
        Includes settings of "Ha-Melekh Shaul ve-ani" and "Yerushalayim, makom sheha-kol zokhrim"
      - "Iri," musical adaptation, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1153)
      - "Jerusalem," program, typescript (2 copies), [1984?] (Box 33, Folder 1154)
      - "Jungles," program, typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1155)
      - "Mearat Tsidkiyahu," chamber poem, program, printed version, 1987 Jun 11 (Box 33, Folder 1156)
      - "Mislosá o arbaá bajéder," musical setting, manuscript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1157)
      - "Mot avi," musical setting, printed version, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 1158)
      - "The Nights to Come," program, film, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1159)
      - "The Quality of Mercy," music series, computer printout, photocopy, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1160)
      - Shaat ha-hesed, selections, printed versions, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1161)
      - "Shene kate makhalah," printed version, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 1162)
        Includes musical settings of Amichai's "Be-terem"
      - "Three Choral Songs on Poems of Amichai," printed version, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 1163)
        Musical settings of "Roshi, roshi," "Arbaah shirim al milhamah ve-shalom" and "Tosefet la-hazon ha-shalom"
      - "Zedekiah's Cave-Chamber poem" or "Mearat Tsikiyahu poemah kamarit," printed program, 1987 Jun 11 (Box 33, Folder 1164)
  - SPEECHES, ADDRESSES, AND LECTURES
    - "1) Peras Agnon 2.) ve-Peras Yerushalayim," notes, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1165)
    - [Acceptance of Honorary Doctorate from Hebrew University], draft and notes, holograph, corrected, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 1166)
    - [Acceptance of Honorary Doctorate from Tel Aviv University], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1167)
    - "Ani maamin be-emunah..." draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1168)
    - "Bi-tekufat Post," draft, holograph photocopy, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1169)
    - [Call to vote for the Havoda Party], drafts, holograph, corrected, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 1170)
    - "Devarim al pigashti im Tselon", draft, holograph, corrected, [196?] (Box 34, Folder 1171)
    - "Devarim al Yitshak Rabin," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1172)
    - "Devarim be-kabalat doktor kavod," draft, holograph, corrected, 1990 Jun 4 (Box 34, Folder 1173)
    - "Devarim li-khevod Tedi ba-asefat behirot 89," draft, holograph, corrected, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 1174)
    - "Der Dichter an der Schwelle zum dritten Jahrtausend," typescript, photocopy (Box 34, Folder 1175)
    - ["Ehad min ha-devarim ha-tovim..."], drafts, holograph, corrected, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 1176)
    - ["Einige Worte zum vorgeschlagenen Thema Kultur und Wissenschaft..."], drafts, holograph, corrected, 1992 May 11 (Box 34, Folder 1177)
    - "El Rubik Rozental," holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1178)
    - ["Every writer uses his own life..."], draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1179)
    - [For Amil Habibi at Van Lear Academy], notes, holograph, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 1180)
    - [For Convention of Israeli, German and Palestinian writers], notes, holograph, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 1181)
    - [For David Yelin's graduation], notes, holograph, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1182)
    - [For International Book Fair opening], notes, holograph, [198?] (Box 34, Folder 1183)
    - [For International Poetry Festival opening], drafts, holograph, corrected, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 1184)
    - [For International Poetry Festival opening], drafts, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1185)
    - [For Israel Festival], draft, holograph, corrected, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 1186)
    - [For Natan Zach], draft, holograph, corrected, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 1187)
    - [For Nobel Prize ceremony], draft, computer printout, [1994] (Box 34, Folder 1188)
    - [For Paulus Böhmer and Gert Loschütz], drafts, holograph, corrected, 1992 Apr 6 (Box 34, Folder 1189)
    - [For Shivifert Prize], draft, holograph, corrected, 1990 (Box 34, Folder 1190)
    - [For Uzi Narkis], notes, typescript and holograph, 1992 Jun 3 (Box 34, Folder 1191)
    - "God Has Pity on Kindergarten Children," draft, fax, corrected, photocopy (Box 34, Folder 1192)
    - "Hartsaah be-universitah im Samot el Kasem," notes, holograph, 1996 Mar 14 (Box 34, Folder 1193)
    - ["He was once asked..."], draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 1194)
    - "ha-Kol ha-hol," outline and draft, holograph, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1195)
    - [Empty folder] (Box 34, Folder 1196)
    - "Language and Literature on the Threshold of the Third Millenium," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 1197)
    - "Le-Franz Viler le-yom huledet 80," notes and drafts, holograph, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1198)
    - "Li-khevod Dan Miron," draft, holograph, corrected (Box 34, Folder 1199)
    - "Literature as Celebration," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1988 (Box 34, Folder 1200)
    - "Mein Judentum," drafts, holograph and typescript, 1978 (Box 34, Folder 1201)
    - [Memorial address for Yitzhak Rabin], draft, holograph, corrected, [1995] (Box 34, Folder 1202)
    - ["Min ha-rega she-bo nifgashti..."], drafts, holograph and computer printout, 1991 Apr 28 (Box 34, Folder 1203)
    - "ha-Moatsah le-tarbut ule-omanut," draft, typescript, 1964 Jun 29 (Box 35, Folder 1204)
    - "Natati le-metargamim li-khetov," draft, holograph, n.d.
    - ["Neesafnu poh ezrahim Yehudim"], drafts, holograph, corrected and clippings, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 1205)
    - "Neum be-tekes mi-siyumim be-universitah," drafts, holograph, corrected, 1989 Jun 11 (Box 35, Folder 1206)
    - [On anniversary of Mishkenot Shaananim], drafts, holograph, corrected, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 1207)
    - [On Israeli-Arab dispute], draft, holograph, corrected, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 1208)
    - "Opening Words for Poetry International 1993," holograph and typescript, 1993 Jun 14 (Box 35, Folder 1209)
    - "Poetry is the Language of the Soul," Honorary Degree Ceremony, Tel Aviv University, printed version (4 copies), 1995 (Box 35, Folder 1210-1211)
    - "Problem of National Identity," speech for the 48th Congres International du Pen, draft and notes, holograph, corrected, 1986 (Box 35, Folder 1212)
    - "Shire milhamah ve-shire ahavah," notes, holograph, 1990 Jun (Box 35, Folder 1213)
    - ["Tears are Israeli writers..."], outline, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1214)
    - ["This is your guardian angel..."], draft, holograph, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1215)
    - "Yisrael 85, le-shalom ve- tsedek hevrati," notes, holograph, 1985 Jan 7 (Box 35, Folder 1216)
    - Untitled, printed version and draft, holograph, 1985, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 1217)
  - OTHER WRITINGS